# RON AHARONI

aharoni.ron@gmail.com borednow.me +972 547 291 244 Tel Aviv, Israel

### **Summary**

Distributed systems engineer and tech leader. Experienced in building resilient and maintainable microservice architectures and stream processing services. My focus is JVM-based services in Scala using functional programming.

Passionate about teaching, learning, and enabling others around me to be more productive.

# Professional Experience

#### Senior Backend Engineer, Mentor, Infra Team, Riskified

2017 — current

- Worked on all aspects of breaking down a monolithic Rails application into Scala microservices: technology selection, developing core libraries, build plugins, and infrastructure, introducing RPC, and setting up CI/CD pipelines.
- Led several microservice migration projects. Projects included data enrichment pipelines, financial transaction processing, and feature engineering.
- As group mentor, was primary technical point of contact to 30 developers, providing daily and ongoing software engineering consulting and lecturing on design, data modelling, and functional programming. Lectured at Scalapeño 2018.
- Coordinated a cross team effort to improve confidence in deployments, by introducing
  integration tests to the company, writing testing infrastructure, and assisting teams in
  incorporating testing in their development cycles.

## Backend Engineer, Corvid Team, Wix

2014 - 2017

- Worked on a platform enabling Wix users to develop and run cloud hosted web applications.
- Developed a distributed, low latency, cost effective, orchestration system for millions of containers running untrusted code.
- Implemented algorithms for efficient resource allocation, fault tolerance and automated recovery.
- Led integration efforts with the Azure cloud, and evaluated performance and stability.

### Data Engineer, Pipl

2013 - 2014

- Worked on a large, custom search system's data processing pipeline.
- Researched and developed supervised learning algorithms to automate data extraction from html pages.
- Implemented a distributed, high throughput system for processing crawl data using Python, Cassandra and Redis.

#### Education

#### M.Sc., Computer Science, IDC Herzliya

2016 - 2020

• Research projects in NLP (paragraph2vec), Dimensionality reduction.

**B.Sc., Computer Science & Bioinformatics**, Hebrew University of Jerusalem 2009 — 2012 • Undergraduate research project focused on predicting protein structure, Furman Lab.

# Skills & Proficiencies

LanguagesScala, Python, Java, {Java, Type}Script (Node.js), SQL, TEXScalaCats, Akka {Http, Streams, Actors}, Shapeless, Slick, sbtPythonscikit-learn, numpy, pandas, matplotlib, networkx, SQLalchemyData & StreamingKafka Streams, Elasticsearch, Cassandra, DynamoDB, Protobuf, Avro,

PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Neo4i

Cloud AWS, Docker, K8S, Argo CI & CD, Helm, Istio, Prometheus